a little programming language.
shell 类似编程语言
And just like JavaScript or Python, it has variables.
就像 JavaScript 或 Python 一样 它具有变量
They look a little different, though.
不过看起来有点不一样
In the Shell, whenever you create or modify a variable,
在 Shell 中 每当你创建或修改一个变量
you just give its name and an equal sign
你只需给它一个名称和一个等号
followed by the value that you want it to have.
后跟你想给它的值
Note, that you can't put any spaces around the equal sign.
记住 等号两边不要加空格
Then when you want to refer to the variable,
然后当你想引用这个变量时
you put a dollar sign in front of its name.
只需用美元符号后跟其名称即可
There are actually two different kinds
Shell 中实际上有两种
of variables in the Shell.
不同类型的变量
One of them is called a Shell variable.
一种叫 Shell 变量
The lines and columns variables that you saw earlier
你之前看到的 LINES 和 COLUMNS 变量
are this kind.
属于这种类型
These are just internal to the Shell program itself.
它们是 Shell 程序本身的内部变量
The other kind is called an environment variable.
另一种叫做环境变量
Environment variables are shared with programs
环境变量是与在 Shell 中
that you run from within the Shell.
运行的程序共享的变量
One environment variable that's really important
一个非常重要的环境变量
is the Path variable.
是 Path 变量
That tells your system where your Program Files are.
它会告诉系统你的程序文件的位置
So when you type a command such as ls,
那么 当你输入一个命令 如 ls 时
it can find the program to run it.
它会找到运行它的程序
For instance, on my system the ls program is in /bin.ls.
例如 在我的系统上 ls 程序位于 /bin.ls 中
So it's in the /bin directory.
所以 它位于 /bin 目录中
And the /bin directory is here in my path variable.
而 /bin 目录可以在我的 PATH 变量中看到
The directories in the path variable
PATH 变量中的目录
are separated by colons.
使用冒号分隔
And the Shell searches them starting with the first one,
Shell 会从第一个开始搜索
and then proceeding to the right until it finds
不断向右 直到找到
the command that you entered.
你输入的命令
And that's how the Shell is able to find the ls command when
这就是当我想运行 ls 命令时
I want to run it.
Shell 找到它的方式
You'll sometimes see instructions
有时你会看到说明
telling you to add a directory to your path
告诉你将一个目录添加到 PATH
so that programs in it can be found.
以便能够找到其中的程序
To add the new directory to the end of your path,
要将新目录添加到路径末尾
you do it like this--
你可以这样写
PATH=$PATH: and then the new directory.
PATH=$PATH: 后跟新目录
But if you do it like this right at the Shell prompt,
但是如果你直接在 Shell 提示符下这么做
that change will only last until you close the Shell.
这个更改只会持续到关闭 Shell 前
We'll take a look at where you do it if you
我们来看看如果你想保留更改
want to keep that change.
应该在哪里执行命令
But first, a couple of quizzes.
但是先来做几个测试题